Guide to the Cleanth Brooks Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1928-86; Series II; 26.5; (64 boxes)
  - BOOKS
    - Wm. Faulkner: The Yoknapatawpha Country
      - Ch. II, "The Plain People: Yeoman Farmers, Sharecroppers, and White Trash"
        - Draft B, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 999)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1000)
      - Ch. III, "Faulkner as Nature Poet"
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1001)
        - Draft A, typescript carbon, corrected, 1963 (Box 56, Folder 1002)
        - Draft B, typescript carbon, corrected, 1963 (Box 56, Folder 1003)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, 1963 (Box 56, Folder 1004)
      - Ch. IV, "The Community and the Pariah" ( Light in August )
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1005)
        - Draft B, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1006)
        - Draft C, typescript carbon, corrected, 1963 (Box 56, Folder 1007)
        - Draft D, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1008)
        - Draft E, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1009)
        - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1010-12)
      - Ch. V, "The Old Order" ( The Unvanquished )
        - Research notes, 1963 (Box 56, Folder 1013-14)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 1015)
        - Draft B, typescript carbon, corrected, 1963 (Box 56, Folder 1016)
        - Draft C, typescript carbon, corrected, 1963 (Box 56, Folder 1017)
        - Draft D, typescript, corrected, 1963 (Box 56, Folder 1018)
        - Draft fragments, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1019)
      - Ch. VI, "The Waste Land: Southern Exposure" ( Sartoris )
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1020)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1021)
        - Draft B, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1022)
      - Ch. VII, "Discovery of Evil" ( Sanctuary and Requiem for a Nun )
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1023-24)
        - Draft A, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1025)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1026)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected (incomplete), 1963 (Box 57, Folder 1027)
        - Draft D, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1028)
        - Chronology of events in Sanctuary, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1029)
        - Note on the chronology of events in Sanctuary, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1030)
      - Ch. VIII, "Odyssey of the Bundrens" ( As I Lay Dying )
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1031-32)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1033)
        - Draft B, typescript, 1963 (Box 57, Folder 1034)
        - Draft B, typescript carbon, 1963 (Box 57, Folder 1035)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1036)
        - Draft D, typescript carbon, corrected, 1962 (Box 57, Folder 1037)
      - Ch. IX, "Faulkner's Savage Arcadia: Frenchman's Bend" ( The Hamlet )
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1038)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1039)
        - Draft B, typescript, 1963 (Box 57, Folder 1040)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, 1963 (Box 57, Folder 1041)
        - Draft D, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1042)
        - Draft E, typescript, corrected, 1963 (Box 57, Folder 1043)
      - Ch. X, "Passion, Marriage, and Bourgeois Respectability" ( The Hamlet )
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1044-45)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1046)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, 1963 (Box 58, Folder 1047)
        - Draft C, typescript, 1963 (Box 58, Folder 1048)
        - Draft D, typescript, corrected, 1963 (Box 58, Folder 1049)
      - Ch. XI, "Passion, Marriage, and Bourgeois Respectability" ( The Town )
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1050)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1051)
        - Draft B, typescript carbon, corrected, 1963 (Box 58, Folder 1052)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, 1963 (Box 58, Folder 1053)
        - Draft D, typescript, corrected, 1963 (Box 58, Folder 1054)
      - Ch. XII, "The Story of the McCaslins" ( Go Down, Moses )
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1055-56)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1057)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, 1963 (Box 58, Folder 1058)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, 1963 (Box 58, Folder 1059)
        - Draft D, typescript carbon, corrected, 1963 (Box 58, Folder 1060)
        - Draft E, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1061)
      - Ch. XIII, "The Community in Action" ( Intruder in the Dust )
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1062-63)
        - Draft A, typescript carbon, corrected, 1963 (Box 58, Folder 1064)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1065)
        - Draft C, typescript and carbon, corrected [3 copies], 1963 (Box 58, Folder 1066)
        - Appendix on Intruder in the Dust, typescript, corrected (Box 58, Folder 1067)
      - Ch. XIV, "History and the Sense of the Tragic" ( Absalom, Absalom! )
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1068-72)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1073)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, 1963 (Box 59, Folder 1074)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, 1963 (Box 59, Folder 1075)
        - Draft D, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1076)
        - Chronology of events, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1077)
      - Ch. XV, "Man, Time, and Eternity" ( The Sound and the Fury )
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1078)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1962 Dec 27 (Box 59, Folder 1079)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, 1963 Jan 21 (Box 59, Folder 1080)
        - Draft C, typescript carbon, corrected, 1963 Jan 21 (Box 59, Folder 1081)
        - Draft D, typescript, corrected, 1963 Jan 26 (Box 59, Folder 1082)
      - Ch. XVI, "The World of William Faulkner" ( The Reivers )
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1083)
        - Draft A, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 59, Folder 1084)
        - Draft B, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 59, Folder 1085)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1086)
        - Draft D, typescript carbon, corrected, 1963 (Box 59, Folder 1087)
        - Draft E, typescript carbon, corrected, 1963 (Box 59, Folder 1088)
        - Draft F, typescript carbon, corrected, 1963 (Box 59, Folder 1089)
      - Character Index
        - Draft A, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 60, Folder 1090)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1091)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1092)
        - Draft D, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1093)
        - Draft E, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1094)
        - Draft F, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1095)
        - Draft G, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1096)
        - Draft H, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1097)
        - Draft I, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1098)
        - Draft J, typescript, corrected, with printer's annotations, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1099)
      - Draft fragments, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 60, Folder 1100-01)
      - Excisions, typescript, 1963 (Box 60, Folder 1102)
      - General research notes, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1103-08)
      - Final draft of text, typescript, corrected, with printer's annotations, pp. i-x, 1-552 (Box 61, Folder 1109-19)
      - Final draft of character index, typescript, corrected, with printer's annotations, pp. 1-121, 1963 (Box 61, Folder 1120-22)
      - Page proofs, corrected, pp. i-xii, 1-499 (Box 62, Folder 1123-32)
      - Page proofs, corrected, with printer's annotations, pp. i-xiv, 1-249, 1963 (Box 62, Folder 1133-37)
      - Page proofs, corrected, with printer's annotations, pp. 250-499, 1963 (Box 63, Folder 1138-42)
      - Publicity
        See: Box 93, folder 1968
      - Book reviews, 1963-67 (Box 63, Folder 1143)
    - William Faulkner: Related Material
      - Biographical material, 1962 (Box 63, Folder 1144)
      - Reference material
        - Literary borrowings in Faulkner's early work, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1145)
        - Notes on Faulkner manuscripts at the University of Virginia, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1146)
        - The South, 1961-83 (Box 63, Folder 1147)
        - Maps of the region, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1148)
        - Miscellaneous, 1976 (Box 63, Folder 1149)
      - Bibliography, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1150)
      - Articles on Faulkner
        - Duclos, Donald P., "Colonel Falkner--Prototype and Influence," typescript (Box 63, Folder 1151)
        - French, Warren G., "The Background of Snopesism in Mississippi," typescript, photocopy (Box 63, Folder 1152)
        - Hegel, Robert L., "Cassius Marcellus Clay and Thomas Sutpen--A 'Lamar Link'?," typescript (Box 63, Folder 1153)
        - Hlavsa, Virginia V., "St John and Frazer in Light in August: Biblical Form and Mythic Function," offprint, 1980 (Box 63, Folder 1154)
        - Meriwether, James B.
          - "Faulkner," offprint, 1973 (Box 63, Folder 1155)
          - "Faulkner and the New Criticism," printed version, photocopy (Box 64, Folder 1156)
          - "Faulkner's Essays on Anderson," typescript, photocopy (Box 64, Folder 1157)
          - "Prolegomena for a CEAA edition of William Faulkner," typescript and printed version, photocopy (Box 64, Folder 1158)
          - "The Short Fiction of William Faulkner: A Bibliography," printed version, photocopy, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1159)
          - "The Text of Faulkner's Books: An Introduction and Some Notes," printed version, photocopy [2 copies] (Box 64, Folder 1160-61)
          - "What Happens When You Eat Magnolias?," typescript, corrected, photocopy, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1162)
        - Morrison, Sister Kristin, "Faulkner's Joe Christmas: Character through Voice," printed version, photocopy, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1163)
        - Perrine, Laurence, "'That Evening Sun': A Skein of Uncertainties," offprint, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1164)
        - Scherting, Jack, "Emily Grierson's Oedipus Complex: Motif, Motive, and Meaning in Faulkner's 'A Rose for Emily,'" printed version, 1980 (Box 64, Folder 1165)
        - Spratling file, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1166)
      - Articles on Faulkner's contemporaries
        - Chabot, Barry, "Allen Tate and the Limits of Tradition," typescript, photocopy (Box 64, Folder 1167)
        - Drake, Robert, "The Lady Frum Somewhere: Flannery O'Connor Then and Now," printed version, photocopy, 1984 (Box 64, Folder 1168)
      - Miscellaneous Articles
        - Netboy, Anthony, "Why the Humanities?," typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1169)
        - "The Vitality of Southern Literature As Seen By Cleanth Brooks," typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1170)
      - Correspondence, 1947-82, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1171)
      - Report on revised Bezzerides script, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1172)
      - Miscellaneous, 1976-82, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1173)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    The Shorter Works subseries consists primarily of essays and lectures. The first half of these is arranged alphabetically by the author being discussed, then by title of that author's works, and finally by title of essay or lecture. The second half is arranged by subject and then by essay or lecture title. The remainder of material in Shorter Works is arranged by type, such as sermons, speeches, book reviews, etc., and thereunder alphabetically by title.
    - Essays and Lectures: Authors and Their Works
      - Auden, W. H.
        "W. H. Auden As a Critic"
        - Research material, 1962, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1174-77)
        - Draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1178)
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1179)
      - Blake, William
        - "Current Critical Theory and the Period Course": typescript carbon, corrected (Box 64, Folder 1180)
      - Coleridge, Samuel Taylor
        "Coleridge As a Metaphysical Poet"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1181)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1182)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1183)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, photocopy, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1184)
        - Draft C, typescript, photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1185)
        - Draft D, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1186)
        - "Coleridge's Biographia Literaria ": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1187)
        - "Coleridge's Three Great Poems"
          - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1188)
          - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1189)
      - Corbett, Richard
        - Unidentified, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1190)
      - Crashaw, Richard
        See: Box 76, folders 1522-24
      - Donne, John
        "Drafts on Poems of John Donne"
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, parts I-II, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1191-92)
        - "John Donne: Wrestling with the Angel": typescript, corrected (Box 65, Folder 1193)
          See also: Box 76, folders 1516-18
      - Eberhart, Richard
        "A Tribute to Richard Eberhart"
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, photocopy, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1194)
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, photocopy, with printer's annotations, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1195)
      - Eliot, T. S.
        - "The Desert, the Garden and the Circle in T. S. Eliot's Poetry": typescript carbon, copies I-II (Box 65, Folder 1196-97)
        - "On Teaching 'The Love Song of J. Alfred Prufrock'"
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1198)
          - Draft B, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1199)
          - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1200)
          - Draft D, typescript, corrected, photocopy, copies I-II, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1201-02)
          - Draft D, typescript, corrected, photocopy, with editor's annotatations, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1203)
          - Correspondence, 1985-86 (Box 65, Folder 1204)
        - "T. S. Eliot and 'Modernism'"
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1983 (Box 65, Folder 1205)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, 1983 (Box 65, Folder 1206)
          - Draft C, typescript carbon, corrected, 1983 (Box 65, Folder 1207)
          - Draft D, typescript carbon, corrected, 1983 (Box 65, Folder 1208)
          - Draft E, typescript, corrected, 1983 (Box 65, Folder 1209)
          - Draft F, typescript, corrected, 1983 (Box 66, Folder 1210)
          - Draft F, typescript, photocopy, 1983 (Box 66, Folder 1211)
          - Draft fragments, 1983 (Box 66, Folder 1212)
        - "T. S. Eliot and the American South"
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1213)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1214)
          - Draft C, typescript, corrected, copies I-III, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1215-17)
        - "T. S. Eliot: Poet and Thinker": research notes, 1983 Apr (Box 66, Folder 1218)
        - "The Waste Land: An Analysis" in A Study of His Writings by Several Hands ed. by B. Rajan: book review, 1948 Jun 13 (Box 66, Folder 1219)
      - Empson, William
        "William Empson: A Tribute"
        - Draft A, holograph, corrected, 1984 (Box 66, Folder 1220)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, 1984 (Box 66, Folder 1221)
        - Galley proofs, photocopy, corrected, 1984 (Box 66, Folder 1222)
      - Faulkner, William
        " Absalom, Absalom !
        - Research notes and draft fragments, holograph and typescript, corrected, parts I-II (Box 66, Folder 1223-24)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1225)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1226)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1227)
        - "The Bear": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1228)
        - "The British Reception of Faulkner"
          - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1229)
          - Draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1230)
        - "Community": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1231)
        - "Crowell Encyclopaedia Article on Faulkner"
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected, ca. 1962 (Box 66, Folder 1232)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, ca. 1962 (Box 66, Folder 1233)
          - Draft B, typescript carbon, corrected, ca. 1962 (Box 66, Folder 1234)
        - "Faulkner and History": typescript, corrected (Box 67, Folder 1235)
        - "Faulkner and the Fugitive- Agrarians"
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, 1981 Aug (Box 67, Folder 1236)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, 1981 Aug (Box 67, Folder 1237)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, photocopy, 1981 Aug (Box 67, Folder 1238)
        - "Faulkner and the Mercantile Spirit": typescript carbon, corrected (Box 67, Folder 1239)
        - "Faulkner and the Muse of History"
          - Research notes, ca. 1975 (Box 67, Folder 1240)
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected, ca. 1975 (Box 67, Folder 1241)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, photocopy, (incomplete), ca. 1975 (Box 67, Folder 1242)
          - Offprint, annotated, 1975 (Box 67, Folder 1243)
        - "Faulkner As a Short Story Writer"
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1244)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1245)
        - "'Faulkner' for A History of Southern Literature "
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1246)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1247)
          - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1248)
          - Correspondence, 1981-82, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1249)
        - "Faulkner's Criticism of Modern America": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1250)
        - "Faulkner's Fauns and Nymphs"
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1251)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1252)
          - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1253)
        - "Faulkner's 'Motherless' Children"
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1254)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1255)
          - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1256)
          - Draft C, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1257)
        - "Faulkner's Possible Debt to Joyce's Ulysses "
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1258)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, photocopy, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1259)
        - "Faulkner's Spiritual and Ethical Values": typescript, photocopy, corrected (Box 67, Folder 1260)
        - "Faulkner's Primitivism": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1261)
        - "Faulkner's The American Dream: What Happened To It? "
          - Research notes, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1262)
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1263)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1264)
        - "Faulkner's Treatment of the Racial Problem: Some Typical Examples"
          - Draft A, typescript carbon, corrected, 1967 (Box 68, Folder 1265)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, 1967 (Box 68, Folder 1266)
          - Draft C, typescript carbon, corrected, 1967 (Box 68, Folder 1267)
        - "Faulkner's Ultimate Values"
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1268)
          - Draft B, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1269)
        - "Faulkner's Vision of Good and Evil"
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1270)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1271)
        - "Foreword to Mrs. Page's Book": typescript, photocopy, corrected, ca. 1972 (Box 68, Folder 1272)
        - "Gavin Stevens and the Chivalric Tradition"
          - Research notes, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1273)
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1274)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1275)
        - "The Image of Helen Baird in Faulkner's Early Poetry and Fiction": typescript, corrected (Box 68, Folder 1276)
        - "Introduction to Light in August ": typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1277)
        - "Langford's 'The Revision of Absalom, Absalom !": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1278)
        - "Mellon Lecture"
          - Research notes and draft fragments, holograph and typescript, parts I-II, 1976 (Box 68, Folder 1279-80)
          - Draft, typescript, corrected, 1976 (Box 68, Folder 1281)
        - " Mosquitoes ": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1282)
        - "Note on the Chronology of Events in Sanctuary ": typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1283)
        - "A Note on Faulkner's Early Short Stories": typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1284)
        - "Notes on Faulkner's Light in August ": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1285)
        - "Notes on Light in August "
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1286)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1287)
          - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1288)
        - "Notes on 'That Evening Sun' and Red Leaves (Box 68, Folder 1289)
        - "Paper on The Wild Palms ": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1290)
        - "Primitivism"
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1291)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1292)
        - "The Province Criticizes the Modern World"
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1293)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1294)
        - "S.A.G.E. Conference on Faulkner: Transcript": draft, typescript, corrected, photocopy, copies I-II, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1295-96)
        - "The Sense of Community in Faulkner's Fiction"
          - Research notes, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1297)
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1298)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1299)
        - "The Southern Review": typescript, corrected, photocopy, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1300)
        - "The Typographical Code Employed in Absalom, Absalom !": typescript, corrected, photocopy, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1301)
        - "William Faulkner--Culture Hero for the Region"
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1981 (Box 69, Folder 1302)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, 1981-85 (Box 69, Folder 1303)
        - "Women in Light in August and The Hamlet "
          - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1304)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1305)
        - Unidentified draft: holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1306)
        - Unidentified draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1307)
        - Unidentified draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1308)
        - Unidentified drafts A and B, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 69, Folder 1309)
      - Frost, Robert
        "Nature and Human Nature in the Poetry of Robert Frost"
        - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1310)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1311)
      - H.D.